Hello and welcome. In this notebook,
大家好在此 notebook 中
we will learn how to use principal component analysis for dimensionality reduction.
我们将学习如何通过 PCA 降维
Dimensionality reduction, is one of the main applications of PCA.
降维是 PCA 的主要用途之一
In the previous lessons,
在之前的课程中
you've already learned how PCA works and about eigenvectors and eigenvalues.
你已经学习了 PCA 的原理以及特征向量和特征值
In this notebook, we will see how to apply PCA to a small dataset.
在此 notebook 中 我们将学习如何向小型数据集应用 PCA
Let's begin by understanding what dimensionality reduction is all about.
首先讲解下什么是降维
Let's suppose we had some two dimensional data that looks like this.
假设我们有这样的二维数据
We can see that most of the data points lie close to a straight line.
可以看出 大部分数据点都紧挨着这条直线
We can also see that most of the variation in the data occurs along this direction,
数据主要在这个方向变化很大
but there's not much variation along this direction.
但是这个方向没什么变化
This means we can explain most of the variation of the data by
我们仅通过查看数据点如何沿着这条直线分布
only looking at how the data points are distributed along this straight line.
就能解释数据的大部分方差
Therefore, we could reduce this two-dimensional data to
所以我们可以将所有数据点投射到这条直线上
one-dimensional data by projecting all these data points onto this straight line.
将这个二维数据降成一维数据
By projecting the data onto a straight line,
通过将数据投射到直线上
we can actually reduce the number of variables needed to describe the data
我们能够减少描述数据所需的变量数量
because you only need one number to
因为只需一个数字就能指定
specify a data point's position along a straight line.
数据点沿着直线的位置
Therefore, the two variables that describe the original data can be
所以描述原始数据的两个变量
replaced by a new variable that actually encodes this linear relationship.
可以替换成一个新的表示这种线性关系的变量
It is important to note that the new variable is
需要注意的是 新的变量只是一种抽象工具
just an abstract tool that allows us to express this data in a more compact form,
使我们能以更紧凑的方式表示这个数据
and may or may not be interpreted as a real-world quantity.
也许是真实的量 也许不是
Now, let's see how we can do this in code.
下面看看如何用代码实现
For simplicity, we will use a small two-dimensional dataset.
为了简单起见 我们将使用小型二维数据集
In a later notebook,
在后面的 notebook 中
you'll get a chance to apply what you learned in this notebook to real stock data.
你将有机会将在此 notebook 中学到的知识应用到实际股票数据上
We will start by creating some randomly correlated data.
首先创建一些随机相关的数据集
In this code, you can choose the range of your data and the amount of correlation.
在此代码中 你可以选择数据范围和相关性
The code outputs a plot with the data points and the amount of correlation.
代码会输出一个包含数据点的图表 并且显示出相关性值
In this case, we chose our data range to be between 10 and 80.
我们将数据范围设成了 10-80
Therefore, the datapoints range between 10 and 80 in both the x and y axis.
数据点在 x 轴和 y 轴的范围都是从 10 到 80
Remember, a correlation of zero means no correlation at all,
注意 相关性为 0 表示完全没有关系
and a correlation of one means complete correlation.
相关性为 1 表示完全相关
You can vary the amount of correlation and create the data that you like.
你可以改变相关性并创建你想要的数据
Once you have created your data,
创建好数据后
the next step in PCA is to center your data around zero.
PCA 的下一步是让数据以零居中
It is also customary to normalize your data.
通常还会归一化数据
This is known as mean normalization.
称之为均值归一化
While centering the data is necessary,
虽然必须居中数据
normalizing the data is optional,
但是不一定要归一化数据
and this is what I have done here.
我归一化了
Mean normalization not only centers your data around zero,
均值归一化不仅使数据以零居中
but also distributes your data evenly,
而且让数据均匀地
in a small interval around zero.
围绕零在很小的间隔内分布
As you can see here,
可以看出
the data is no longer in the range between 10 and 80.
数据范围不再是 10到 80
But after normalization, the data is now distributed between minus three and three.
归一化之后 数据现在的范围是 -3 到 3
This will help your algorithm converge faster.
这样可以提高算法的收敛速度
With our data centered,
居中数据后
we're ready to perform PCA.
我们就可以进行主成分分析了
To do this, we will use a package called Scikit-learn.
我们将使用软件包 Scikit-Learn
Scikit-learn's PCA class allows us to easily implement PCA on data.
Scikit-Learn 的 PCA 类可以使我们轻松地对数据进行主成分分析
The first thing we need to do is to create a PCA object with
首先需要根据一组给定的参数创建一个 PCA 对象
a given set of parameters including the number of principal components we want to use.
参数包括要使用的主成分数量
We'll start by using two components because we want to visualize them later.
我们将使用两个成分 因为稍后需要可视化它们
Here, we can see the parameters that the PCA algorithm is going to use.
这些是 PCA 算法将使用的参数
The next step is to pass the data to the PC object using the fit method. A quick note.
下一步 使用 fit 方法将数据传递给 PC 对象小贴士
In Scikit-Learn, the PCA algorithm automatically centers the data for you.
在 Scikit-Learn 中 PCA 算法会自动为你居中数据
So, you could pass the original dataset to
所以可以将原始数据集传入 fit 方法中
the fit method instead of the normalized data as we have done here.
而不用传入我们在这里归一化的数据
Once we fit the data,
拟合数据后
we can use the attributes of the PCA class to see
我们可以使用 PCA() 类的属性
the eigenvectors also known as the principle components, and its eigenvalues.
查看特征向量（亦称为主成分）及其特征值
One important attribute of the PCA class is the explained variance ratio.
PCA() 类有一个重要属性是方差贡献率
The explained variance ratio gives us the percentage
方差贡献率表示
of variance explained by each of the principal components.
每个主成分能解释的方差百分比
In general, the principle components with
通常 特征值最大的主成分
the largest eigenvalues explain the majority of the variance,
能解释大部分方差
and this is usually the ones that we want to keep.
我们通常希望保留这些主成分
For example, here we can see that
例如 从这里可以看到
the first principle component explains 94 percent of the variance,
第一个主成分解释了 94% 的方差
and has the largest eigenvalue.
并且特征值最大
Now that we have the principle components,
获得主成分后
we can visualize them.
就可以可视化它们了
Here, we see the data with the first principle component,
这些是具有第一个主成分和
and the second principle component.
第二个主成分的数据
We can see that the first principal component lies
可以看出 第一个主成分
along the direction in which the data varies the most.
沿着数据变化最大的方向
One question that you will frequently face
你经常会遇到的一个问题是
is how many principal components you should use.
应该使用多少个主成分
For example, suppose you had a dataset with 1,000 dimensions.
例如 假设数据集有 1,000 个维度
Should you reduce this dataset to
你应该将数据集降到 500 个维度
500 dimensions or could you do better and reduce it to 100 dimensions?
还是进一步降到 100 个维度？
Usually, the number of principal components is chosen
通常 选择多少个主成分
depending on how much of the variance of the original data you want to retain.
取决于你要从原始数据中保留多少方差
For example, you may want to retain 90 percent of the variance,
例如 你可能想保留 90% 的方差
or you may only want to retain 50 percent of the variance.
或者只想保留 50% 的方差
You can use the explained variance ratio attribute of the PCA class
你可以使用 PCA() 类的方差贡献率
to determine the number of components you need to
决定保留多少个主成分
keep to retain a given amount of variance.
从而保留指定的方差量
For example, if you wanted to retain 90 percent of the variance,
例如 如果你想保留 90% 的方差
you can add up the elements in
可以将方差贡献率数组中的元素加起来
the explained variance ratio array until the desired value is reached.
直到达到想要的值
The number of elements you had to add up to reach
达到目标值所需的元素数量
the desired value determines the number of
就是保留一定的方差量
principal components needed to retain that level of variance.
所需的主成分数量
For example, if you had to add up five elements to retain 90 percent of the variance,
例如 如果你需要将 5 个元素加起来 才能保留 90% 的方差
then you will need five principal components.
那么需要 5 个主成分
Now, that we have seen what all the principal components look like,
我们已经知道所有的主成分
we will now use PCA to perform dimensionality reduction.
现在将利用 PCA 降维
Since the data we're using in this simple example only has two dimensions,
因为在这个小示例中使用的数据只有两个维度
the best we can do, is to reduce it to one dimension.
所以我们最多只能降到一维
So, now choose the number of
现在 将 PCA 算法中的
principle components in our PCA algorithm to be equal to one.
主成分数量设为 1
Once we ran the PC algorithm with only one component,
运行只有一个成分的 PCA 算法后
we can see what the transform data looks like by
我们可以使用 PCA() 类的 transform 方法
using the transform method of the PCA class.
查看转换后的数据看起来如何
In this simple case,
在这个简单示例中
the transform method projects the data onto
transform 方法将数据投射到了第一个主成分上
the first principal component so we will just get a straight line.
所以只有一条直线
When working with higher dimensional data,
在处理更高维度的数据时
the transform method will project the data onto
transform 方法会将数据
the lower-dimensional surface determined by
投射到更低维度的表面上
the number of principal components you used in your algorithm.
这个表面由你在算法中使用的主成分数量决定